Huh? You sure you got that?
Don't strain yourself.
Well, that's it.
Turned in my key.
Yep. No turning back now.
You still think
this is a good idea?
What, me driving
this thing?
I told you,
I'm more than happy
to let you drive.
No, this,
moving in with you.
Having this baby.
Jessie, you're the best thing
that ever happened to me.
I've been ready for this
for a long time.
I just remembered
the weirdest dream
I had last night.
It's the last chance
to remove it.
A little more suction, please.
Can't see a thing in there.
It's skull.
It's part of
the guy's skull.
Intertrochanteric fracture
in your hip.
Your left clavicle
and three ribs
are shattered.
You've got compound fractures
in your right and left tibia.
Good news is
you will walk again
within three or
four months of therapy.
My baby?
I'm sorry.
I know
it's been a long haul
for you, Jessie.
But we'll still need
to send a physical
therapist to you at home.
Can someone
come pick you up?
Your mother or father?
Uh, my mom
died of cancer
when I was a baby,
and my father gave me
to my aunt to be raised
after my mom died.
I haven't seen him
in years.
Miss Laurent,
can he come here
to pick you up?
Dad?
Thanks for picking
me up, Dad.
Hmm. Glad I could help.
Sorry about
your boyfriend.
This was your mother's room.
You're gonna have to
stay in here.
The other bedrooms
are upstairs.
Let's get you in bed.
When your aunt passed
away, they gave me some
things you had there.
Clothes.
You hungry?
I could make you
a sandwich or something.
Uh...
No, I'm fine.
Just tired is all.
Oh, yeah,
the water out of the tap
sometimes comes out bad.
You just
let it run a little,
it'll clear up.
Preston.
Dad?
You here?
Oh, my word.
Thank you, Mama.
Ahh!
Hello, Jessabelle.
Mom.
I went back and
forth 100 times
whether or not
this was a good idea.
Making these tapes.
But as you can see,
here I am.
It is March 14,
and it is 1988,
and I am seven months
pregnant with you.
I love you, Jessabelle.
I love you.
If you're watching this,
it means I'm gone.
But I don't want this
to be a day of sadness.
I want it to be
a day of happiness.
So I'm not even
gonna talk about me.
The only thing
that's important
is that you know
that I love you.
And that I have been
watching over you, always.
Okay. So, enough
of that sad shit.
I told your father
that I wanted him
to give you this tape
on your 18th birthday.
So for you,
it is 2006.
Happy Birthday!
Happy Birthday, baby!
I thought about
having a cake,
but explaining all
this to Mrs. Davis
just would have been
a little too weird.
Uh, Mrs. Davis
is our cook,
and if she's there,
could you tell her
I said hi?
She's so sweet.
That ought to freak
her out, though.
She is scared of ghosts.
Whoo-oo-oo!
Anyway, um, I wanted
to make this tape
because I wanted you
to get to know me.
And I wanted to give
you a birthday gift,
a birthday reading
with my cards.
I am really
good at this.
I'm always right.
You can't cut the deck,
so this will have to do.
Here we go.
I still have
your bracelet, Mom.
Okay. So this is Death.
But it doesn't
mean "death" death.
It means transition.
And this year,
your 18th year,
is gonna be
a year of transition.
You know what it says here?
It says that you've
never left St. Francis
and that you're
never gonna leave.
Baby, you've gotta
get out there
and see the world.
There's so much
great stuff out there.
Suits of Cups.
That's the water sign,
and water is pragmatic.
It goes the way
of least resistance.
But this is
a lot of water.
Are you a swimmer,
or do you do something
with the sea?
I can't even swim.
You're a homebody,
just like your mama.
Wrong again.
You're terrible at this!
Well, it says here
that you're not alone.
That there is a presence
in the house with you.
It's not a bad thing.
There are guardian
angels everywhere.
Maybe I'm seeing me.
Uh!
Yes, so she's a she.
It's a female.
Um...
She wants you
out of the house.
She says it's hers.
Jesus, Dad!
You scared the
shit out of me!
Where did you get that?
I asked you
a goddamn question!
I said, "Where did
you get that?"
I found it in my room,
in Mom's room.
Don't, Dad! Don't!
What are you doing?
Dad, what are you doing?
Oh! No, Dad.
Oh, God, Dad.
No more snooping around.
Dad? Dad?
Dad.
Dad!
It's past your bedtime,
sweetie.
That there is a presence
in the house with you.
Who are you?
Jessabelle.
I made breakfast.
Look, I'm sorry
about last night.
I was a little drunk.
It's not gonna
happen again.
It's all right.
That was your
mother's old chair.
It was out
in the shed.
Didn't expect to see
your mother last night.
That tape,
I didn't know
she made that tape,
that she actually
went through with it.
You just found
that one tape?
Uh-huh, just one.
Hello, Jessabelle.
I love you.
I love you too, Mom.
It's been three weeks
since our last reading.
There was so much
weird stuff in there,
so I asked Moses about it.
Not Ten Commandments Moses,
but my friend Moses
from my church
on Jerry's Creek.
Don't tell Dad.
He'd kill me.
Moses taught me
how to read cards.
So I showed him your reading,
and he said something
interesting.
He said that the two
presences in the house,
the two females,
they're both you.
You've been having
nightmares, right?
And when you see it,
this presence,
it's broken, right?
It's a demon,
but it's an inner demon.
You were in some
sort of accident
or something,
or maybe somebody
you know was.
Now, I want you
to listen to me.
It wasn't your fault.
Stop blaming
yourself, sweetheart.
It wasn't your fault. Okay?
Now that we know
that's what that
last reading meant...
I mean, that's what
Moses says.
So, we're gonna
get you a new one.
All right.
Death. That means transition.
You really don't have
to worry about that.
I see a very
horrible death.
Dad?
Miss Laurent?
I was knocking,
but I know you're
in a wheelchair,
so I got in.
Hi. It's just Jessie.
Uh, the hospital told you
I was coming, right?
Uh, no.
Um, yes. Yes.
Oh.
You must be Miss Arlenna.
Rosaura.
You can call me Rosaura.
It's great to meet you.
Let's get started.
Okay. Okay.
You feel good?
I'll be back and
check on you, okay?
Mmm-hmm.
No, no!
What the
hell's going on?
Just calm down.
Settle down.
It's nothing.
Where the hell
were you? Huh?
I'm sorry.
I'm so sorry, Mr. Laurent.
It was only five minutes.
Get out! Now.
I'm sorry.
Get out!
What did you mean
by "nothing", Dad?
What's nothing?
What are you doing?
It's her goddamn tapes!
She's got you
scared out of your mind.
I told her not to do this.
But, Dad, it's Mom.
It's all I have of her!
That thing on these tapes
is not your mother.
Five weeks
into her pregnancy,
we found out
she had tumors
in her brain.
She wouldn't do chemo.
Nothing to help herself.
It ate her mind, the cancer.
It just wasn't her anymore.
But, Dad, I want
to watch them!
Why? So she can scare
the shit out of you
some more?
I'm gonna
burn these tapes.
Dad, no!
No, Dad!
Don't, Dad! Dad!
Dad.
Oh, God!
Dad! Dad!
Jessie!
No! Dad!
Dad!
Goodbye, Leon.
May your soul finally
find peace. Amen.
Hey, Jessie.
Preston.
How you been?
Uh...
That was a really
stupid question.
I heard you were
in town last week.
I would have come over,
but I figured I should
call first.
I tried you a few times,
but no one picked up.
I'm sorry.
My Dad's phone
is upstairs,
and it's gonna be
a few more weeks
before I can walk
upstairs to answer it.
Right. I'm sorry.
It's really good
to see you, Preston.
It's good to
see you, too.
I'm really sorry
about your dad.
Jessie?
Jessie, you okay?
Hey.
Morning.
Good morning.
Uh...
You stayed here all night?
Yeah, well,
I figured I'd stick around,
make sure you're okay.
Thanks.
You didn't have to.
Well, I guess I should
get going home.
But I'd love to see
you again, though.
Be okay if I come
by some other time?
Yeah. Yeah, I'd like that.
All right.
You take care.
Uh, wait, wait.
Please don't go.
What?
If I don't talk to
somebody, I'm gonna
go crazy.
Maybe I already am crazy.
Okay.
I don't gotta
go anywhere.
I'll stay right here.
Thank you.
But you think we can
get the hell out of
this place?
Kind of gives me
the creeps.
Yeah.
Pretty much
everybody's still here.
Rick Foster just got
back from Afghanistan.
But he's going back, I think.
He's still married
to Shawna.
If I was married to Shawna,
I'd be going back, too.
Mary Kimball's
been married
and divorced twice.
Twice?
She's got three kids.
Lives in that
new subdivision
over by the quarry.
The quarry.
So, the quarry's
still there, huh?
Yes, well, you know,
it is a big, giant hole.
You can't really move
a big, giant hole.
Smart ass.
Cut me some slack.
Yeah.
Nothing's changed, really.
Marriages and mortgages.
I can see
why you couldn't
get out fast enough.
Uh...
Preston, I'm so sorry.
Hey, you don't
gotta explain to me.
If I'd gotten into college,
I would've left this town
and never looked back.
Never would have
given it a second thought.
That's not true.
I thought about
this place a lot.
I missed you.
I'm sorry
I didn't call more.
I just wanted
a clean breakaway,
I guess.
But me leaving
never had anything
to do with you.
It's okay.
I understand.
How have you been?
Married.
Oh, uh...
Where did she think
you were last night?
Oh, I told her the truth.
I told her I was
with a Make-A-Wish kid.
So tell me
what's going on.
Oh...
You seemed so
scared back there.
Um, okay.
I've been
having nightmares.
I've been having
really bad dreams,
and they're so
real that I think
I'm going crazy.
I dreamed
there's this girl.
She looks dead,
and she's trying
to get me, kill me.
And there's this man.
It looks like he's
been burnt to death,
and he looks at me
like I did it.
Like whatever
happened to him,
it was my fault.
Well, after everything
you've been through,
it would be weird
if you weren't having
nightmares, right?
Have you thought
about seeing a shrink?
I can't afford it.
I mean, if I had
any money at all,
I wouldn't have come
home to live with Dad.
I'm flat broke.
And there are these tapes.
Now that we know
that's what that
last reading meant...
I mean, that's what
Moses says.
So, we're gonna
get you a new one.
I really don't think
you should be watching
these anymore.
It's no wonder
why you're having
nightmares.
It's not good for you.
Would you watch them
if it was your mom?
Your only chance
to get to know her?
Yeah, I would, but I'd wait,
wait until I was recuperated.
Not when I was still
stuck in this house
where she died.
I mean,
it's just weird.
And besides,
she's wrong more
than she's right.
She said you
never left town,
you love to swim.
She said Dad
was gonna die.
No, she thought
you were gonna die.
She said 10 things
that were wrong,
and you picked one
that was almost right.
Jessie,
she didn't predict
your dad's death.
She thought she
saw your death,
and she was wrong
about everything.
Now, look,
I've been thinking
about your dreams.
That girl you keep
seeing, it's you.
And the guy that
burnt in the fire,
you're having a nightmare
about your accident.
Shit, that's my wife.
I'm sorry,
but I've gotta go.
Here. That's my work cell.
It's got my home
phone number on it.
You call me any time,
day or night, all right?
Promise?
Okay.
I'm sorry. I gotta go.
Thank you, Preston.
Yeah, of course.
Now you take care.
This is beautiful
South Louisiana.
And here is the belle
of South Louisiana.
That's right. Here she is.
I'm gonna send
this to Mr. Hugh Hefner,
and I'm gonna
make me some money
on the side.
The most beautiful woman
in South Louisiana.
Bad.
- This is the family portrait.
-   Wait a minute. Wait.
I might just
send me some tapes
to that Mr. Hugh Hefner.
These bugs
are eating my ass up!
- Let's see those feet.
- Where'd they go?
There it is.
Oh! There she is.
Baby!
Hey, baby, you
can't improve perfection.
Look at that.
What are you doing?
Recording
for posterity.
Those who don't
remember the past are
doomed to repeat it.
Okay, well, let's
go into the future.
Merry Christmas!
Merry Christmas! Yeah!
Now, listen,
I want to show you
how to use it.
You just take it,
point it, and shoot it.
You got it?
Okay, you got it?
Just hold it.
Merry Christmas!
Mrs. Davis,
I think these people
are about ready to eat.
They're gonna
eat the furniture
if we don't sit them
down and feed them.
I'm gonna do the thing.
What? Okay.
Let's work
with this, okay?
Excuse me.
Before you unwrap the presents
and get into some funky music,
I just wanted to take
a little second here
to brag about something.
Oh, yeah, surprise.
How very unlike you, Leon.
Now wait a minute.
It has come to my attention
that my lovely,
devoted wife
is with child.
I'm pregnant!
Raise your
glasses and toast
to Leon and Kate!
Congratulations.
I can drink.
You're already dead,
Jessabelle.
You're already dead!
Preston? I'm sorry.
I know I said I
wouldn't call, but...
Who is this?
Uh...
It's Jessie,
Jessie Laurent.
Who is this?
Come closer.
Closer.
Yes.
Hey. You all right?
Sam just told me
you called last night.
I'm all right.
I'm so sorry.
I just got scared.
Everything okay at home?
Well, "okay" is
stretching it a bit,
but I'm fine.
Well, I'm glad
you're here.
All right.
Well, tell me
what happened.
Oh, you see that, too?
Yeah.
What is that?
I don't know.
I think somebody's
out there.
There was somebody
definitely out
there last night.
You think that old
boat still works?
Sure.
What is that?
Mmm. Some kind of
voodoo or something.
Half the cemeteries
in this parish are
full of that kind of shit.
But why would they
put it on our land?
Yeah,
someone's definitely
been out here, all right.
That's pretty fresh.
What?
There's something
down there.
What is that?
What are you doing?
This isn't my first
time in the bayou.
Hmm.
That's weird.
That's my birthday.
Why would someone
want to spook you
like this?
Or maybe that's
a real gravestone.
Maybe you had a twin
sister or something.
I never had a sister.
And why would we both
have the same name?
I don't know.
I've got cousins with two
Beauregards in their family.
They just like the name.
But who killed that chicken?
And who brings flowers?
Do you think
there's something
under that stone?
All right.
I guess we'll go back
to your house and see
what kind of tools you've got.
Uh!
You don't recall any mention
of your parents having
another little girl?
Hmm.
Well, you were
right to call us.
I suspect
it was a stillbirth.
We'll run some tests,
find out if she was
a relative of yours
based on your DNA sample.
Of course we have
a sample of your daddy
already from his autopsy.
So we'll give you a call
when we find out
who this infant was.
Thank you, Sheriff.
We knew we had to
call you right away.
Remind me again the nature
of your relationship
with Miss Laurent.
We're old friends
from high school.
Y'all have
a good night, then.
Thank you, Sheriff.
You know you can't
stay here, right?
I've got nowhere
else to go.
Yeah, you do.
You all right?
Yeah.
Hey, honey.
Hey, Sam, this is Jessie.
Jessie, this is Sam, my wife.
It's almost 1:00 a.m.
I gotta work tomorrow.
Yeah, I know.
Um, this is my fault.
I'm so sorry.
I'm the one
who dragged him
all into this.
We don't have an extra room.
Hope the couch
is okay for you.
Yeah, it's fine.
I need to get to bed.
Thank...
I'm sorry about that.
Undo these.
Yeah.
Okay, now.
Yeah, thanks.
All right.
Well, just let me know
if you need anything else.
Thank you.
Night.
I'm sorry for getting you
in trouble last night.
That's all right.
That's what old
friends are for.
You're just lucky you were
asleep when she left
for work this morning.
I see.
Yeah. So why do you
wanna go to Woodbury?
Well, I think there's
somebody who might know
who that baby girl is.
Do you remember
Scott Davis from school?
Yeah, I remember him.
His mom, Abbey, used to
cook for my mom and dad
back before I was born.
Well, if she's still alive,
I'll take you there.
Excuse me, sir.
Abigail Davis
live here?
Thank you.
Mrs. Davis?
Hey, Mrs. Davis.
I used to go to school
with your son, Scott.
It's Preston.
Remember me?
Me and Scott used
to play together
when we were little.
You used to yell at us
for jumping off your garage.
Remember?
Preston Saunders.
You're gonna break
your arm up there,
and I'm gonna
laugh my ass off.
It's good to
see you, Mrs. Davis.
It's been a long time.
There's someone else here
to see you. This is Jessie.
Jessie Laurent.
You used to cook
for her folks.
Jessie Laurent?
Mmm-hmm.
Jessabelle!
Mrs. Davis.
God, is she all right?
What did she say?
I don't know.
She say,
"Rain wet us, Mama.
"Sun dried us, Papa.
"The betrayers are evil.
"Call down Djowou.
Call down Djowou
will deal with them."
What's that mean?
It's an old song
from Haiti.
They sing it to
call the spirits
to possess someone.
Tell Moses Jessabelle
get what's coming to her!
You okay?
Goddamn voodoo shit.
I always hated
Scott's mom.
Jessie, don't worry.
It's just some
crazy old lady.
Probably says shit
like that all the time.
What does that mean
"they call the spirits
to get possessed"?
On purpose?
Well, yeah.
In voodoo, possession
ain't a bad thing.
What?
Yeah, it's part of
their ceremonies.
You call down the spirits,
and they possess you,
and you dance around.
That's what they do.
How do you know that?
You grew up here, too.
There's voodoo
all around this place.
They really get possessed?
Well, that depends
on who you ask.
I think it's like hypnosis.
You know,
like faith-healing,
speaking in tongues.
If you're raised
to believe that,
that's what you're
gonna think is real.
Plus they've got drums going,
people dancing around.
They rub blood on you.
You think you're possessed.
"Moses".
She said, "Tell Moses."
I don't know.
Voodoo mixes all kinds of
religions, Catholic, African.
It's all the same to them.
No, my mom knew a Moses.
She said that on the tape.
She learned tarot
cards from Moses
at her church.
I think her church
was somewhere out
near Jerry's Creek.
God damn it.
Well, I guess you get to see
my patented 175-point turn.
No, wait, wait, wait.
What's that?
"Moses Harper.
Born December 12th, 1952.
"Died June 12th, 1988."
"Legba, open the gate.
Legba, let Moses back in."
Get out.
I'm Preston.
This here is my friend...
Let's go, Preston.
Look, now, we don't
want any trouble.
Hey! Stop it!
Wait!
- Preston, you all right?
- Go!
You're not
coming back here.
Ever. There's no way.
Preston...
You're not
gonna stay here.
You go in.
Get whatever you need.
You can stay with us again.
Your wife's gonna be
thrilled about that.
You could stay
at my mom's.
My mom always
liked you.
You know that.
She's still got
our prom pictures up.
That's another reason
why Sam's not
so crazy about you.
She knows I still
think about you.
And she knows
we're probably
gonna move on.
But you didn't do it, Jessie.
Not you showing up right now.
It's just weird
timing is all.
All right. I'm gonna
get you out of here.
Ready?
Yeah.
Excuse me.
All right,
let's get
you packed.
Would you grab
me that bag?
Yeah.
Here you go.
Thank you.
I'll get this
over here.
Preston?
All right.
Be right back.
You ready? All right.
Preston?
Oh! Preston!
Your boyfriend is
in shock, but his
blood pressure is okay.
He should be fine
when he comes to,
but they're running
him to the hospital
just to be safe.
He's not my boyfriend.
We were just friends
from high school.
Miss Laurent,
do you mind telling me
what the hell's going on here?
We don't have the results
back on the DNA yet.
But that infant we found,
we do know was a female.
The date on her gravestone
was probably about right.
Well, then was
she a stillborn?
No, she wasn't.
She was born alive.
They know that.
Then she was murdered.
What?
From the nature
of the fractures
and the splintering
of the vertebrae,
it seems like somebody
just picked her up
and snapped her over his knee
like a piece of firewood.
She was murdered.
Miss Laurent, I don't know
what the hell is going on
around here,
but clearly,
you are one very
frightened young woman.
She doesn't
want to hurt us.
What?
She needs our help.
Who?
Uh...
Sheriff, would you mind
calling me when Preston
wakes up, please?
All right.
Please call me
when you know
he's all right.
All right.
I know you were murdered.
What are you
trying to tell me?
Who were you?
Please,
I wanna help you.
Who are you?
Jessabelle.
What do you
want from me?
Hello? Hello?
It's Sheriff Pruitt.
Your boyfriend's come to.
He seems all right.
I thought
you'd wanna know.
Oh, he's all right?
The paramedics
said he should rest.
He won't even go
to the hospital
for an exam.
He wants me to take him
back out to the house
to protect you
from something.
Do you know
what that is?
Sheriff, I can
barely hear you.
Miss Laurent, we also
just got the results back
from the DNA test.
That deceased baby girl
that you dug up was black.
What did you say?
She was black?
I don't understand.
Does that mean she
was my half-sister?
They crossed your DNA
with your father's,
with Leon's...
What?
That's you crying.
You're crying
'cause you're scared.
You don't know where you are.
You don't know who you are.
You don't know shit!
I'm gonna tell you
who you are.
Because that's what
good mothers do.
Jessabelle, you're dead.
Your father's dead.
Moses.
No, it's all gonna be
all right, isn't it?
I need you, sugar.
I need you. Good girl.
You're gonna come back.
I'm gonna hold the door
open for you.
Jessabelle,
you're gonna get
what's coming to you!
The unwanted presence
in the house.
When you see it,
it's broken, right?
It wasn't the ghost.
It was me.
You were telling
someone else's fortune,
weren't you?
You know what it says here?
It says that you've
never left St. Francis
and that you're
never gonna leave.
Your real daughter,
not me.
You gave your life
for Jessabelle.
Didn't do chemo.
When the baby was born,
it wasn't Dad's.
No, no!
He killed her,
didn't he?
Moses taught me
how to read cards.
Look at those.
Don't tell Dad.
He'd kill me.
So Leon adopted a baby girl
to cover the crime?
A white girl, me.
Your church,
Moses' church.
Get out.
They gave her the grave.
What do you
want from me?
What can I do?
Moses.
What are you doing?
Payback.
What?
No! No.
It's not my fault!
Somebody!
Help!
No! What do you
want from me?
All Jessabelle wants
is what's coming to her.
Somebody! No! No!
Let me go!
What is...
No, no, no!
No!
Please don't.
Where are you taking me?
No, God! Please.
Please!
Jessie!
Please! Help me!
No! God!
Oh, my God!
Hold on. Hold on.
You all right?
I thought I lost you.
Take me home, my love.
Miss Laurent?
Are you all right?
Miss Laurent!
It's Jessabelle.